<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ELA | Cyclohexane >_<]]></title>
  <link href="http://zhantongz.github.io//github/categories/ela/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zhantongz.github.io//github/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-27T05:29:12+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://zhantongz.github.io//github/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zhantong Zhang]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ELA 30-1 Exit Project]]></title>
    <link href="http://zhantongz.github.io//github/2014/05/20/ela-30-1-exit-project/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-20T06:33:20+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://zhantongz.github.io//github/2014/05/20/ela-30-1-exit-project</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am working on it ^_^&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ELA 20-1 Brave New World Background Info.]]></title>
    <link href="http://zhantongz.github.io//github/2013/11/29/ela-20-1-brave-new-world-info/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-29T07:45:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://zhantongz.github.io//github/2013/11/29/ela-20-1-brave-new-world-info</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Background Information</h2>

<h4>Technology Development with Utopia and Dystopia</h4>

<p>When Huxley wrote Brave New World, the Western society has completed industrialization and colonized many regions in the World with new weapon technologies. In 1920s and 1930s, huge development in technologies such as television, more wider radio system and mass production of cars and planes also caused the raising of consumerism. People were enjoying variety of entertainment and spend money on industrial products. In this context, people were looking forward a utopia.</p>

<p>A utopia is an ideal society that provides</p>

<!--more-->


<p>all the needs for people. Technology advancement fulfills people’s needs of matter. Narcotic drugs are also found and used as “happiness pill” to fulfill mental needs. People at that time thought that an ideal world was coming without pain, disease, etc. as Huxley describes in the novel. The World State is a state that all people are “truly” happy in the exchange of freedom. The state has very advanced technology including mass production of human, harmless drug. The babies are treated in a special facility. All human are trained from the born that they are good and happy, they are glad about their caste. For the purpose of running the state, the castes are used to give different people different rules and abilities.</p>

<p>In that “ideal” society, however, is not actually ideal. Huxley builds the “ideal” society to prove utopia is dystopia. A dystopia is a extremely bad society. In the World State, people are without any freedom. All the happiness is taught by the state. People are no longer real people. Huxley believes that technological advancement not necessarily leads to an ideal society but a society without real people.</p>

<h4>Historical References related to Soviet Union in Chapter I to VI</h4>

<p>In Brave New World, Huxley refers to many people and events happened at his time including Henry Ford, Karl Marx, establishment of Soviet Union, etc. The people referred to are most the ones who represent an ideology. Due to the WWI and the Great Depression, the socialist/communist ideology was raising and the Russian Revolution caused a communist regime. There are many allusions made related to Soviet Union.</p>

<p>In the Chapter II, the allusions are made by describing the process of letting children hate books and flowers. The Director says the reason for hating flowers is that there will not be enough people working if they loves the nature. It is related to СССР as the state encourages people to work for communism/state.</p>

<p>At the beginning of Chapter III, Polly Trotsky is referring to Leon Trotsky who was one of the leaders of Soviet Union but was exiled because he was against Stalin’s dictatorship. That the Director asks P. Trotsky out is a symbol for the exile of L. Trotsky and that L. Trotsky created the Fourth International for his own Trotskyism. The Director represents СССР, a totalitarian state just as the World State.</p>

<p>As well in the Chapter III, the Controller express the detriment of home, family, parents, etc. The Controller express the same propaganda as the Soviet Union that all people should work for the state in order to achieve social stability and give up self for the whole good. The hates of liberalism, (English) democracy and religion for the good of the state (everyone) are also identical to СССР.</p>

<p>As the first thinker of communism, Karl Marx is called Bernard Marx. Bernard is possibly referred to George Bernard Shaw who advocated for women rights. In the novel, Marx is from the Bureau of Psychology as Marx is the philosopher/ideologist who directs the development of СССР at first. The events of talking between Lenina (Vladimir Lenin) and Marx represent Marxism-Leninism, the Lenin’s understanding of Marxist communism. As Bernard is a feminist, he feels bad about Lenina who is used as a tool of the state (that Stalin used Lenin to achieve dictatorship). As well, Lenina does not understand Marx even they believe the “same” state showing that the revision of Marxist communism which is a totalitarian ideology developed further by Stalin.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
