<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Politics | Cyclohexane >_<]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.zhantong.org/categories/politics/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.zhantong.org/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-13T01:33:30+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.zhantong.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zhantong Zhang]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Complaint to the Competition Bureau]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.zhantong.org/2014/07/13/a-complaint-to-the-competition-bureau/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-13T00:44:10+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.zhantong.org/2014/07/13/a-complaint-to-the-competition-bureau</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After I got my new laptop, a ThinkPad L440 with Windows 8 pre-installed, I filed a complaint against Microsoft and Lenovo this thurday (Jul. 10, 2014) for tied-selling of the computer and Microsoft Windows 8 to the Competition Bureau of the government of Canada. <a href="%22http://cpbl.wordpress.com/2010/11/04/tied-selling-of-windows-os-with-computer-hardware-in-canada-a-complaint-to-the-competition-bureau/">The Red Pen</a> tried this before and the Bureau, in my opinion, did not respond appropriately because their conduct is anti-competitive. Although it is highly likely that the Bureau reacts the same, I filed the complaint to express my concern about Microsoft monopoly. I encourage you to do so if you are in Canada and in a similar circumstance so that the government one day may choose to put an end. If you are in another country, I hope you can find a way to complain to your government according to similar laws, e.g. State Administration for Industry and Commerce in China who is responsible for the enforcement of 《中华人民共和国反不正当竞争法》; and in most countries, you can always file a lawsuit asking for refund in a small claims court. Complain text is attached.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Complaint text (with a few grammar/spelling corrections and omission of personal informations):</p>

<blockquote><p> On one day, I ordered a ThinkPad L440 Laptop from Lenovo Canada. When I purchased a ThinkPad L440 laptop from Lenovo website, I did not have any option to avoid purchasing one of Windows 8.1, Windows 7 Professional and Windows 8.1 Pro which all are products supplied by Microsoft, and which I do not want because I do not accept the user agreements which I have to accept to use them. In order to purchase the laptop, I chose Windows 8.1 option. The agreement, on the computer I received on another day, prevents me from using the software without accepting it and I may return to the manufacturer, Lenovo, according to the manufacturer&rsquo;s policy requiring me to return the hardware, too. I then removed Windows from my hard drive and installed Arch Linux, another operating system, to use the computer for its intended purpose when purchasing. The conduct of Lenovo and Microsoft concerns me because it negatively affects competition in operating system market and requires customers to pay for a software they may not want.
  Under s. 77 of the Competition Act, the practice of tied-selling, which exists when a supplier (Lenovo), as a condition of supplying a particular product (ThinkPad L440), requires or induces a customer to buy a second product (Windows), can be prohibited if it is engaged in by a major supplier and is likely to lessen the competition.
  In this case, Lenovo and Microsoft are major suppliers in PC market and operating system market. Lenovo’s worldwide market share in the first quarter was 19.2 percent, which is the largest in the world, based on <a href="www.newsobserver.com/2014/07/10/3996839/lenovo-bolsters-its-no-1-status.html">www.newsobserver.com/2014/07/10/3996839/lenovo-bolsters-its-no-1-status.html</a>. Microsoft shares 91.53 percent of all non-mobile computers (including laptops) according to <a href="[http://www.netmarketshare.com/">http://www.netmarketshare.com/</a>, and the market share is higher excluding Mac OS as Mac OS only supplies to Apple products.
  Their conduct can and is likely to lessen the competition in the operating system market by discouraging the entry of other competing systems. By pre-installing Windows and not offering other options, they increase the efforts needed for users to install another system as pre-existing systems may have already configured BIOS, hard drive, etc. that can cause problems in an installation of other systems. As the price includes the price of Windows, users are likely not to relinquish the software they paid for without the option of partial refund, consequently, they are not likely to try a new operating system. The tied-selling restricts the competition by discouraging users to use product from other supplier and thus discouraging a supplier&rsquo;s entry, or expansion into the market.
  As a result, the current anti-competitive practice of Lenovo and Microsoft shall be prohibited and partial refund should be offered to those who were required to buy Windows when purchasing a laptop though they did not want it and never activate Windows after rejecting its user agreement.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
